<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fragments on xyz prashish</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/fragments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fragments on xyz prashish</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/fragments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Going Abroad Scenario</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fragments/the-going-abroad-scenario/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fragments/the-going-abroad-scenario/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the thought process of a young student looking to go abroad without really thinking it through, simply because everyone else is doing the same. Here&amp;rsquo;s a grade 12g student from Nepal who wants to leave just because everyone else is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1: Contemplation (Thinking):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Look how clean those streets are.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everyone abroad looks so successful.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;No load shedding, no bandhs.&amp;rdquo; (power cuts, strikes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2: Attachment (Wanting):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;That could be me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I want that life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m wasting my potential here.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maya</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fragments/maya/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fragments/maya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working in tech for the past decade, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about this concept called &lt;em&gt;Maya&lt;/em&gt; and how it maps to what I see around me. The tech industry feels like &lt;em&gt;Maya&lt;/em&gt; in action. Not sure why this keeps bugging me. &lt;em&gt;This is Maya.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You start as a junior developer, excited about every new library, every framework, convinced you&amp;rsquo;re building the future. Then you become senior, and you watch the next wave of juniors get excited about&amp;hellip; the exact same things. Different names, same energy. React becomes Vue becomes Svelte becomes whatever&amp;rsquo;s next. Microservices become serverless become edge computing. &lt;em&gt;This is Maya.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vajrapani The Senior Engineer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fragments/vajrapani-the-senior-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fragments/vajrapani-the-senior-engineer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came across a story in Buddhist literature that has been on my mind ever since. &lt;em&gt;Vajrapani&lt;/em&gt;, known for raw power, went to &lt;em&gt;Buddha&lt;/em&gt; (the enlightened being) and asked for wisdom. &lt;em&gt;Vajrapani&lt;/em&gt; already had the strength to get things done by sheer force and power, but he wanted to know what makes effort truly meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It reminded me of engineers I know who can go deep into the codebase, fix tricky bugs, and ship features, but often only see their piece of the puzzle. What they miss is how it connects with everything else , marketing trying to explain the product, customer service handling frustrated users, finance keeping the lights on, or founders shifting direction after talking to customers and the changing dynamics of the market.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pain of Not Doing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fragments/the-pain-of-not-doing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fragments/the-pain-of-not-doing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like to work with people who are &lt;em&gt;intensely passionate&lt;/em&gt; about what they do. It does not matter what the field is. It could be nurturing kids, reading, writing poems, solving scientific problems, or coding a simple database service. What matters is the feeling inside, whether it is fire or love that comes from the heart. It is hard to reason and explain, but it can be understood from the depth of the inner being. It is the kind of passion that makes you forget food, water, and time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back to Writing, Thanks to AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fragments/back-to-writing-thanks-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fragments/back-to-writing-thanks-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The progress of AI keeps surprising me, even when I expect it to work. This blog was built in 2018 when I was experimenting with Jekyll and Hugo late at night, mostly to see if I could get something working.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since then I tried several times to bring it back, but the system (dependencies) was outdated and would not compile. I got busy, left it aside, and never returned to it. Every now and then I thought about fixing it. Even when a colleague helped, we could not get it running.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes From My AI Shelf</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fragments/notes-from-my-ai-shelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fragments/notes-from-my-ai-shelf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months I have found myself surrounded by books, talks and podcasts on AI. I pick one up in the evenings, sometimes just to flip through a chapter, other times to get lost in the stories of how this technology came to be and might turn out to be.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Age of AI&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Genesis&lt;/em&gt; explore the wider consequences of how this technology could shape our lives and societies. Books like &lt;em&gt;AI Valley&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;AI Rising&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Chip War&lt;/em&gt; bring a more geographical perspective, tracing how AI rose in different parts of the world and inside the companies that pushed it forward. Reading them feels almost like going through autobiographies of industries, and I enjoy that part a lot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI and Creative Workflow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fragments/ai-and-creative-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fragments/ai-and-creative-workflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2015, I came across Tim Urban’s fascinating post about AGI (Artificial General Intelligence) and ASI (Artificial Superintelligence). It was an interesting read, but it was not an &amp;ldquo;aha&amp;rdquo; moment for me at the time. My exposure to AI (or machine learning back then) was mostly through its use in engineering systems such as fraud detection, recommendation engines, and pattern recognition tools in our payment infrastructure. It felt more like solving backend challenges than experiencing anything magical.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Joy of Walking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fragments/the-joy-of-walking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fragments/the-joy-of-walking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think the best way to explore a city is by walking. No doubt about it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whenever I travel, whether it is for a conference, a meeting, or an event, I try to carve out some time just to walk. During Token 2049 in Singapore a few years back, where the schedule was packed with side events scattered across the city, I made it a point to walk from one to the other whenever I could. The city is small, and it is lovely to move through it on foot. It was not only about getting from point A to point B, but about slowing down after a long day and pausing for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fully On-Chain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fragments/fully-on-chain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fragments/fully-on-chain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digital ownership is what makes blockchain exciting for me. For the first time, you can actually hold something that does not vanish just because a company shuts down or pulls the plug on its servers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In games, we never had that. I spent endless hours in FIFA, Age of Empires, DOTA, and I don’t really have anything to show for it now. When the next version came out or a server went offline, everything I built disappeared. Meanwhile, I still have a box of toys and cards from when I was younger. They are still there, still mine, carrying little pieces of memory. Digital worlds never gave us that sense of permanence, because they were never designed to. They always belonged to someone else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10,000 Books</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fragments/10000-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fragments/10000-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right now my private library holds a little over a thousand books, but I like to imagine it one day reaching ten thousand. Not because I will ever read them all, but because collecting books feels like collecting seeds of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When someone visits for the first time, I often hand them a book from the shelf. Inside the first page I note when and where I bought it, so they know this book had its own little journey before reaching them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/on-integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 02:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/on-integrity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Handshake deals are the best kind of business deals. People come together, discuss their ideas and shake on it. No legal paperwork, just trust and the promise of work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Integrity: the quality of being honest and having strong moral principles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having the right ingredients of integrity will set the foundation for handshake deals. Being honest to yourself &amp;amp; others is the key to building long-term partnerships, and to creating something valuable together. Because it is impossible to start a business with someone who doesn’t pass your &lt;a href=&#34;https://organizationalphysics.com/2016/06/21/how-full-is-your-trust-battery/&#34;&gt;trust threshold&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing more or less</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing-less-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 14:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing-less-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My virtual mentors for writing are &lt;a href=&#34;https://waitbutwhy.com/&#34;&gt;Tim Urban&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://sivers.org/&#34;&gt;Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt;. These two incredible human beings have a completely different writing styles. Tim writes long articles narrating as the first person and every nooks and corner of the subject. Derek writes short, crisp and valuable life lessons. My favorites are &lt;a href=&#34;https://waitbutwhy.com/2014/05/fermi-paradox.html&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://waitbutwhy.com/2015/01/artificial-intelligence-revolution-1.html&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sivers.org/hellyeah&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sivers.org/evers&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inspired by them, I tried writing a couple of drafts for #abakgarne. But it turned out horrible and, most importantly, didn’t capture my intention nor thought. It felt forced, and I had to scratch my head to write them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fat wallets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fat-wallets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 14:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fat-wallets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I paid all my orders in cash because my previous debit card was not active. But most stores didn’t accept cards anyways. This has remained the same for a long time. I hardly noticed any store with a card reader, unlike the stores in California.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Things are changing though. The government is pushing for digital &amp;amp; cashless payment. And e-wallets are popping up everywhere. I even gave a crash course to my dad on e-wallets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Inspiration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/on-finding-inspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 14:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/on-finding-inspiration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People have asked me a countless number of times why I moved back. I have been pondering over this for some time. For the last few weeks, I have been looking for my “inspiration”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We find inspiration in unknown places. Places which, by nature, engulf your existence and take you to a land of discovery. The discovery isn’t through the act of finding the meaning though, but by traveling through the journey. The journey might not have checkpoints nor cheerleaders, but characters who went through their paths to connect the dots going backward. Last few weeks, these characters have been my imaginary friends from &lt;strong&gt;books on history and biography.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Same ‘ol Kathmandu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/same-old-ktm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 14:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/same-old-ktm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To be honest, Kathmandu hasn’t changed a lot. I see the same shops, the same restaurants, the same school buses, the same गल्लि (small roads) at the same spots where I left them five years ago. Things have remained the same for the better, or for the worse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate to meet a lot of people last week that I would have met in six months in California. My phone was ringing instead of buzzing, which says that people still prefer calling instead of texting in Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fragments/joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 06:23:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fragments/joy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“What sparks joy?” — Wow, such a simple but complicated question to think about.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first sentence that mapped on my head when I thought about this was — “What makes me happy?” Yeps, what are the things that make me happy? Period. Move along.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But it cannot be this simple, right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I used to think that there are certain things that would always make me happy (or spark joy), many small/big things that I always look forward to doing. Those activities that I could fall back to when I need to find happiness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Driving Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/mozdrive-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 18:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/mozdrive-end/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every Mozillian that I have met are passionate about their work. There is no ‘I’ in the community. This sense of togetherness isn&amp;rsquo;t common in today&amp;rsquo;s selfish world. And to be part of this community makes me a proud Mozillian. I could have easily spent my 25-days break completing full seasons of TV series. Or, if I wanted to be productive.. work on a hobby project. Both of them sounded fun as per my liking. However, that’s not what Mozillians do. A Mozillian would spend their free time taking actions to build communities. A Mozillian would work to make the web free and open. A Mozillian would create a movement. That’s what I wanted to do too. I wanted to inspire thousands of Mozillians to push themselves in making them their dream, a reality. That’s the reason I set out on this incredible journey &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mozdrive&#34;&gt;to travel around the United States&lt;/a&gt; to spread the love about Mozilla and the Open Web.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
