<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fragments on xyz prashish</title>
    <link>https://prashish.xyz/fragments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fragments on xyz prashish</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://prashish.xyz/fragments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI and Creative Workflow</title>
      <link>https://prashish.xyz/ai-and-creative-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prashish.xyz/ai-and-creative-workflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2015, I came across Tim Urban’s fascinating post about AGI (Artificial General Intelligence) and ASI (Artificial Superintelligence). It was an interesting read, but it was not an &amp;ldquo;aha&amp;rdquo; moment for me at the time. My exposure to AI (or machine learning back then) was mostly through its use in engineering systems such as fraud detection, recommendation engines, and pattern recognition tools in our payment infrastructure. It felt more like solving backend challenges than experiencing anything magical.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrity</title>
      <link>https://prashish.xyz/on-integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 02:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prashish.xyz/on-integrity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Handshake deals are the best kind of business deals. People come together, discuss their ideas and shake on it. No legal paperwork, just trust and the promise of work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Integrity: the quality of being honest and having strong moral principles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having the right ingredients of integrity will set the foundation for handshake deals. Being honest to yourself &amp;amp; others is the key to building long-term partnerships, and to creating something valuable together. Because it is impossible to start a business with someone who doesn’t pass your &lt;a href=&#34;https://organizationalphysics.com/2016/06/21/how-full-is-your-trust-battery/&#34;&gt;trust threshold&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing more or less</title>
      <link>https://prashish.xyz/writing-less-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 14:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prashish.xyz/writing-less-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My virtual mentors for writing are &lt;a href=&#34;https://waitbutwhy.com/&#34;&gt;Tim Urban&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://sivers.org/&#34;&gt;Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt;. These two incredible human beings have a completely different writing styles. Tim writes long articles narrating as the first person and every nooks and corner of the subject. Derek writes short, crisp and valuable life lessons. My favorites are &lt;a href=&#34;https://waitbutwhy.com/2014/05/fermi-paradox.html&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://waitbutwhy.com/2015/01/artificial-intelligence-revolution-1.html&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sivers.org/hellyeah&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sivers.org/evers&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inspired by them, I tried writing a couple of drafts for #abakgarne. But it turned out horrible and, most importantly, didn’t capture my intention nor thought. It felt forced, and I had to scratch my head to write them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fat wallets</title>
      <link>https://prashish.xyz/fat-wallets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 14:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prashish.xyz/fat-wallets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I paid all my orders in cash because my previous debit card was not active. But most stores didn’t accept cards anyways. This has remained the same for a long time. I hardly noticed any store with a card reader, unlike the stores in California.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Things are changing though. The government is pushing for digital &amp;amp; cashless payment. And e-wallets are popping up everywhere. I even gave a crash course to my dad on e-wallets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Inspiration</title>
      <link>https://prashish.xyz/on-finding-inspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 14:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prashish.xyz/on-finding-inspiration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People have asked me a countless number of times why I moved back. I have been pondering over this for some time. For the last few weeks, I have been looking for my “inspiration”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We find inspiration in unknown places. Places which, by nature, engulf your existence and take you to a land of discovery. The discovery isn’t through the act of finding the meaning though, but by traveling through the journey. The journey might not have checkpoints nor cheerleaders, but characters who went through their paths to connect the dots going backward. Last few weeks, these characters have been my imaginary friends from &lt;strong&gt;books on history and biography.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Same ‘ol Kathmandu</title>
      <link>https://prashish.xyz/same-old-ktm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 14:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prashish.xyz/same-old-ktm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To be honest, Kathmandu hasn’t changed a lot. I see the same shops, the same restaurants, the same school buses, the same गल्लि (small roads) at the same spots where I left them five years ago. Things have remained the same for the better, or for the worse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate to meet a lot of people last week that I would have met in six months in California. My phone was ringing instead of buzzing, which says that people still prefer calling instead of texting in Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joy</title>
      <link>https://prashish.xyz/sparkjoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 06:23:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prashish.xyz/sparkjoy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“What sparks joy?” — Wow, such a simple but complicated question to think about.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first sentence that mapped on my head when I thought about this was — “What makes me happy?” Yeps, what are the things that make me happy? Period. Move along.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But it cannot be this simple, right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I used to think that there are certain things that would always make me happy (or spark joy), many small/big things that I always look forward to doing. Those activities that I could fall back to when I need to find happiness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Driving Force</title>
      <link>https://prashish.xyz/mozdrive-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 18:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prashish.xyz/mozdrive-end/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every Mozillian that I have met are passionate about their work. There is no ‘I’ in the community. This sense of togetherness isn&amp;rsquo;t common in today&amp;rsquo;s selfish world. And to be part of this community makes me a proud Mozillian. I could have easily spent my 25-days break completing full seasons of TV series. Or, if I wanted to be productive.. work on a hobby project. Both of them sounded fun as per my liking. However, that’s not what Mozillians do. A Mozillian would spend their free time taking actions to build communities. A Mozillian would work to make the web free and open. A Mozillian would create a movement. That’s what I wanted to do too. I wanted to inspire thousands of Mozillians to push themselves in making them their dream, a reality. That’s the reason I set out on this incredible journey &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mozdrive&#34;&gt;to travel around the United States&lt;/a&gt; to spread the love about Mozilla and the Open Web.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
